你走下楼梯  看到了一个木制宝箱
You walk down a hallway and come to a wooden chest.
脑灰质大人  你打算怎么做
Lord Gray Matter, what do you do?
我用我的匕首戳弄宝箱  试探有无陷阱
I poke it with my dagger to see if there are any traps.
没有陷阱
There are no traps.
火焰喙  你打算怎么做
Fire Beak, what do you do?
-比利  -干嘛
- Billy? - What?
你就是火焰喙
You are Fire Beak.
好吧
Okay.
所以你打算怎么做
So what do you do?
我是火焰喙
I'm Fire Beak.
小家伙们  我准备了点心
Hey, guys, I brought snacks.
谢谢妈妈
Thanks, Mom.
你们在玩什么桌游  梯子和滑道吗
What are y'all playing, Chutes and Ladders?
丹在教我们玩《龙与地下城》
Tam is teaching us Dungeons & Dragons.
我们正在进行
We're on a quest to find
寻找恶魔巴尔泽布的恶魔之叉的任务
the pitchfork of a devil named Baalzebul.
我是火焰喙
I'm Fire Beak.
这就是那个恶魔吗
And is this the devil?
不是  他只是一个不穿裤子的怪兽
No, he's just a monster who doesn't wear pants.
好吧
Oh, I see.
是的  他就让那玩意在外面露着
Yes, oh, he's just hanging right out there, isn't he?
好吧
Okay, well...
孩子们玩得愉快
You kids have fun.
我妈妈不相信有精灵
My mother didn't believe in elves,
妖精  和龙
fairies, or dragons.
乔治
George!
但她相信有恶魔
But she did believe in the devil.
而她并不觉得
And she did not view him
它适合当她儿子的玩伴
as an appropriate playmate for her son.
乔治
George!
♪ 世上没人比我强壮 ♪
♪ Nobody else is stronger than I am ♪
♪ 昨天我移了一座山 ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ 我相信我能当你的英雄 ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ 我是个了不起的小家伙 ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
少
年
谢尔顿
我真的很担心
I'm worried.
这书里面有能召唤真正恶魔的咒语
There are incantations in this book to summon actual demons.
怪不得我们身边有这位恶魔
Is that how we wound up with you?
蛮好笑的  所以我饶你一命
That's a good one. I'm gonna give you that.
不要不当回事
This is not a joke.
这就是教会里有警告过的
This is one of the children's games
那种不恰当的小孩游戏
we were warned about in church.
那就跟他说不许玩啊
Then tell him to stop playing.
哪有这么简单
It's not that easy.
他好不容易交了几个朋友
He's finally got a couple of friends.
我不想吓跑他朋友
I don't want to scare them off.
等哪天你想吓跑小朋友时
Well, when you're ready to scare kids,
这张吓人脸随时恭候差遣
you got this face locked and loaded.
够了  上一个还蛮好笑的
All right, the other one was funny,
这一个就只是你在嘴贱
now you're just being a jackass.
你们俩玩得高兴我很开心
I'm glad you're both amused,
但我们的宝贝儿子的灵魂可能有危险呢
but our little boy's soul may be at stake.
拜托
Come on.
我小时候我也听了很多黑色安息日乐队
When I was a kid, we were listening to Black Sabbath,
他们唱了一堆恶魔有关的歌
all that devil music.
我也平安无事啊
Didn't hurt me.
撒旦也没来收割我的灵魂
Satan didn't get my soul.
那你灵魂上哪去了  拿去换甜甜圈吃了吗
What happened to it? You trade it for some donuts?
你自找的
You had that one coming.
你好  斯巴克斯先生
Hello? Mr. Sparks?
-你好啊 玛丽  -现在有空吗
- Oh, hello, Mary. - Got a minute?
有啊  什么事
Sure, what's up?
我有点担心孩子们玩的一个游戏
Um, I was just concerned about a game that the boys were playing
不晓得你们夫妇知不知道这个事情
and was wondering if you and your wife knew about it.
游戏吗
A game?
是的  一个非常不妥的游戏
Yes, a very disturbing one.
你说的是什么游戏
Well, what're we talking about?
你发现他们在互抓屁股吗
Did you catch those boys playing grab ass?
不是  是《龙与地下城》
No. Dungeons & Dragons.
所以大家的裤子都有穿着是吗
So everybody's got their trousers up?
-是的  -那有啥问题啊
Yes. ?What's the problem?
这游戏里有恶魔学
The game contains demonology,
那内容违反了教会的教导
which goes against the teachings of the church.
但没有人随便乱摸别人  对吧
But nobody's touching nothing, right?
没有
No.
那我不知道你有什么好担心的啊
Well, then I don't quite know what you're worried about.
-你不知道吗  -不知道
- You don't? - Nope.
我只感恩比利交到了朋友
I'm just thankful Billy found some friends
而且不再吃泥土与马厩草了
and he ain't eating dirt and crabgrass any more.
也不知道什么时候  他突然就爱吃那些
Some point, he just got a taste for it.
说个不相关的
On an unrelated note, uh,
你最近有改变发型还是做头发吗
you doing something new with your hair?
看起来好美啊
It looks, uh, real pretty.
没有  但谢谢夸奖
No, but thank you.
好了  我不打扰你忙了
Okay, well, I'm gonna leave you to it.
也很好闻
Smells good, too.
好的  再见
All right. Bye-bye.
你们晚饭想吃鸡吗
Hey, you want chicken for dinner?
我现在就去帮你宰一只肥的
I'll slaughter a big one for you right now.
不用了  谢谢
I'm good.
我还是先杀一只  免得你改变主意吧
I'll kill one in case you change your mind.
你们谁已经活腻了
Now which one of you's tired of this life?
就你吧
You.
打扰了  阮先生
Excuse me, Mr. Nguyen?
你好
Yes?
您应该不认识我  我是谢尔顿的妈妈
Hi, you don't know me. I'm Sheldon's mother.
那个聪明孩子
Ah, the smart boy.
是的  那个聪明孩子
Yes, the smart boy.
你很幸运啊
You are lucky.
有个聪明的儿子是很幸福的事
To have a smart son is a great joy.
而我没有这种幸福
I do not have that joy.
肯定不是这样的
Oh, I'm sure that's not true.
我想请问一下  您知道丹跟谢尔顿
Listen, are you aware that Tam and Sheldon
在玩一个叫《龙与地下城》的游戏吗
are playing Dungeons & Dragons?
《龙与地下城》吗
Dungeons & Dragons?
是的  里面充斥着各种恶魔与撒旦的图像
Yes, and it's filled with demons and satanic images.
你来跟这个白人女人谈吧  我很忙
但我也有客人要照顾啊
拜托啦  我都没对你有什么要求
你也没给我多少东西啊
所以这游戏是有什么问题
So what is the problem with this game?
问题在于
The problem is,
这内容有违教会的教导
it goes against the teachings of the church.
好的  请听我说
All right. Listen to me.
在越共的再教育营里被饿死  那是个问题
A problem is starving to death in a Communist reeducation camp.
你多年不能见自己家人
A problem is not seeing your family for many years
还得去为胡志明小径扫除地雷时  那是个问题
while you remove land mines from the Ho Chi Minh trail.
一个里面有幻想恶魔的小男生游戏
A game boys play with make-believe demons,
不是个问题
not a problem.
我觉得这些都算得上是问题啊
Well... I think they can all be problems.
你就假装附和她  她就会走了
对不起  我同意你的说法
I'm sorry, I agree with you.
我会去跟丹谈谈
I will talk to Tam.
那太好了  谢谢您
Oh, good. Thank you.
那不打扰了  很高兴认识你
Well, bye. Nice meeting you.
五块钱
Five dollars.
牧师
So, Pastor...
最近教会还好吗
How's things going at the church?
不用客气  叫我杰夫就行
Please, call me Jeff.
教会一切都很好
And everything's going great
因为我有最赞的老板
'cause I have the coolest boss.
不好意思  但我实在
I'm sorry, but I'm kind of having a hard time
无法理解圣灵叫你杰夫
feeling the Holy Spirit calling you Jeff.
我还是就叫你牧师吧
I'm-I'm gonna stick with Pastor.
没问题
Sure.
谢谢你了  牧师
Thank you, Pastor.
没错  这样感觉舒服多了
Yeah, that feels better.
太感谢你来一趟了  杰夫牧师
So nice of you to come over, Pastor Jeff.
他喜欢人家叫他杰夫
He prefers Jeff.
我就要叫他牧师
I'm sticking with Pastor.
等等  我改变主意了  我要叫你牧杰[PJ]
Wait, I changed my mind. I'm going with PJ.
缩写跟睡衣一样  不过也没事
Brings to mind pajamas, but that's fine, too.
言归正传  抱歉把您请过来处理
Anyway, I'm sorry to drag you into this,
但这事跟恶魔有关  所以是您的管辖范围
but it is demons, so it's in your purview.
的确是
It is indeed.
其实在最近的年轻浸信会领导会议
In fact, at a recent Young Baptist Leaders Conference,
我还去了撒旦娱乐活动研讨班
I attended a seminar on satanic leisure activities.
然后呢
And?
然后重点就是
And the important lesson is,
与其让父母或权威人物
rather than have a parent or authority figure
来把这犯戒的游戏拿走
take the offending game away,
让神来拿走它  连根拔起
let God remove it, root and stem.
提问  牧杰
Question, PJ.
上头的大佬怎么做到这事呢
Uh, how's the big guy do that?
很简单  谢尔顿得来主日学校
Simple, Sheldon needs to start attending Sunday school.
如果他喜欢有恶魔与魔鬼的书
If he likes books with demons and devils,
我这里有一本书能让他心醉神迷
I've got one that will blow his mind.
什么书
What book is that?
《圣经》啊  乔治
The Bible, George.
当然啦
Sure, yeah.
我觉得这个主意太棒了
I think that's a wonderful idea.
不过我有点担心
Although, I am concerned
谢尔顿可能会有些反抗
that we may get a little pushback from Sheldon.
有些吗
A little?
不要  我才不去
No, I won't go.
我不信神
I don't believe in God.
现在你信不信并不是重点
Well, now, what you believe in is not the point.
玛丽  请让我...
Mary, if I may...
谢尔顿  我知道你有一天想当科学家
Sheldon, I understand you hope to be a scientist someday.
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
那我问你一个问题
Well, let me ask you a question.
你说你不相信神
You say you don't believe in God,
但什么样的科学家会
but what kind of scientist comes to a conclusion
不做任何研究就下结论呢
without first doing the research?
烂科学家
A bad scientist.
没错
That's right.
那我们周日早上八点见吧
So I'll see you Sunday morning at 8:00.
不会见到我的
No, you won't.
我对自己施放二级法术隐身术
I cast a second level spell of invisibility on myself.
那游戏绝对没让他变聪明
Well, that game isn't making him any smarter.
谢利  你为什么还不睡觉
Shelly, why aren't you asleep?
我在为主日学校做预习
I'm studying for Sunday school.
你在读圣经吗
You're reading the Bible?
太好了
That's wonderful.
我有个问题
I do have a question.
没问题  你问吧
Sure, what?
我们镇上有人是亚玛力部落的吗
Is there anyone in our town from the Amalek tribe?
我不知道呢  怎么了
I don't know, why?
按书上说法  我们应该杀了他们与他们的牛
If there is, we're supposed to kill them and their cows.
没有  没有亚玛力人
Well, no. There's no Amaleks.
我就跟你说吧
Told you.
不叫我们遇见试探
And lead us not into temptation,
救我们脱离凶恶
but deliver us from evil.
因为国度
For thine is the kingdom
权柄  荣耀
and the power and the glory
全是你的  直到永远  阿门
forever and ever. Amen.
-阿门  -非常好
- Amen! - Very good.
我们今天早上开始前
Now before we get started this morning,
我想跟大家介绍两位新学生
I want to introduce two new students,
谢尔顿与米希·库珀
Sheldon and Missy Cooper.
让我们来欢迎他们
Let's give them a warm welcome.
怎么了  比利
Yes, Billy?
我认识他们
I know them.
谢谢你  比利
Thank you, Billy.
不客气  杰夫牧师
You're welcome, Pastor Jeff.
上周呢
Now, uh, last week,
我们开始讲了约翰福音
we started talking about the Gospel of John.
有人有任何
Does anybody have a notion
对神在那里面要说的话的见解吗
as to what God's getting at in that passage?
来  谢尔顿
Yes, Sheldon?
约翰福音第一章第一节写到
Chapter one, verse one states,
"太初有道
"In the beginning was the Word,
道与神同在  道就是神"
and the Word was with God and the Word was God."
非常好
Well done.
谢谢  我昨晚读了这福音
Thank you. I read the gospels last night.
马屁精
Suck up.
你知道当《圣经》里写到"道"的时候
Did you know when the Bible says "The Word"
是从最初的希腊语"逻各斯"而来的吗
they're translating the Greek expression "logos"
而"逻各斯"的意思就是知识
and logos means knowledge.
看来某人很有"逻各斯"呢
Sounds like someone has a noggin full of "logos."
比利  你说
Yes, Billy?
我们住同一条街
They live on my block.
太棒了
Terrific.
真不敢相信他在读《圣经》
I can't believe he's reading the Bible.
对啊
I know.
我其实还挺感谢《龙与地下城》这游戏
I'm actually grateful to that Dungeons & Dragons game.
它帮助我们带他走向神
It helped lead him to God.
别说神的事了
Ixnay on the Odsgay.
完事了
I'm done.
你读完了吗
You finished it?
全读完了  考我什么鸟是犹太洁食
All of it. Ask me which birds are kosher.
这饵我咬了  什么鸟是犹太洁食
I'll bite. Which birds are kosher?
鸡  是  鹌鹑  也是
Chickens, yes. Quail, yes.
猫头鹰  没想到居然不是
Owls, surprisingly no.
反正它们身上也没多少肉
Well, there ain't a lot of meat on them anyway.
谢利
Shelly,
我很高兴你对宗教产生了兴趣
I'm so happy you're taking an interest in religion.
是啊
I am.
所以我决定要再去了解其他宗教
And I've decided to explore other religions, too.
你说什么
What's this, now?
杰夫牧师鼓励我
Pastor Jeff encouraged me
要用科学的方法接触宗教
to approach religion scientifically,
所以丰富我的资料库是很合理的
so it only makes sense to enlarge my database.
不  你的知识储备就是基督教浸信会
No, your database is Baptist.
你只需要这些资料就够了
That's all the data you need.
浸信会资料
Baptist data.
你还考虑了其他哪些宗教
What other religions you considering?
佛教  犹太教
Buddhist, Jewish,
印度教  天主教  全都考虑
Hindu, Catholic, all of them.
不  不行
Nope. Nope.
不许这样
That's not happening.
为什么
Well, why?
身为一个美国人  我难道没有信仰自由吗
As an American, don't I have freedom of religion?
现在龙与地下城那些玩意儿
Those dungeons and dragons are looking pretty good
感觉没那么糟了吧
right now, aren't they?
我还想要研究巫毒教
I'm also looking into voodoo.
丹  你信仰天主教对吧
Tam, you're Catholic, right?
是啊
Yes.
跟我讲讲
Explain it to me.
讲什么
Explain what?
比如先说说  你向谁祷告
Well, for starters, who do you pray to?
大概是  耶稣  上帝与圣母玛利亚
I guess, Jesus, God and Mary.
耶稣不是上帝吗
Jesus isn't God?
不是  耶稣是上帝的儿子
No, he's his son.
但你吃祂肉  喝祂血
But you do eat him, and drink his blood.
还有个圣神[鬼]
Oh, there's also a ghost,
但不是恐怖的那种鬼
but not the scary kind.
像电影《鬼马小精灵》吗
Like Casper?
是的
Exactly.
那教宗是干嘛的
And how does the pope work?
教宗住在意大利梵蒂冈
Well, the pope lives in Italy.
他有特殊的教宗座驾  还有一顶大尖帽
He has a special car, and a big pointy hat.
是一顶超赞的帽子
It's a wonderful hat.
还有什么我应该知道的东西吗
And is there anything else I should know about?
你时不时
Every once in a while,
就得去找一个神父告解罪恶
you have to confess your sins to a priest.
我不用  我没有任何罪恶
Not me, I don't have any sins.
那你有傲慢之罪
Then you have the sin of pride.
你的宗教让我自我感觉好差
Your religion is making me feel bad.
这样你才知道有效啊
That's how you know it's working.
哈钦斯女士  你信仰什么宗教呢
Ms. Hutchins, what's your religion?
我信仰摩门教  怎么了
I'm a Mormon, why?
我在做一个调查报告
I'm conducting a research project.
你能跟我说说摩门教吗
Can you tell me about being a Mormon?
这是在纽约创立的
Well, it started in New York,
有个人发现了一个被埋在地底的金页片
when a man found gold plates buried underground.
金页片上写了
The plates said that,
当我们去世之后  我们会飞升到自己的星球
when we die, we get to go to our own planet.
除非你是个女人
Unless you're a woman,
那你就会飞升到你丈夫的星球
then you have to go to your husband's planet.
但我不会有这个问题
But that won't be a problem for me.
因为我没有老公
I don't have a husband.
我只有我的喵星人
All I have is a cat.
一只又胖又凶的喵星人
A big, mean cat.
或许我有机会去它的星球
Maybe I'll get to go to his planet.
喵星球上的孤寡谢丽尔
Lonely Cheryl on Planet Cat.
我喜欢她  她好有意思
I like her. She's funny.
你会喜欢艾拉的  他人很好
You're gonna love Ira. He's a great guy.
他是你的男朋友吗
Is he your boyfriend?
是我其中一个  所以别提这方面的事
Well, he's one of them, so let's not bring that up.
现在方便吗
Is this a good time?
当然啦  请进  请进
Absolutely. Come in, come in.
艾拉  这是我外孙  谢尔顿
Ira, this is my grandson Sheldon.
谢尔顿  这是我朋友艾拉
Sheldon, this is my friend Ira.
-你好啊  -你好
- Hello. - Howdy.
姥姥跟我说你是犹太人
So Meemaw tells me you're Jewish.
开门见山
Right to it, huh?
行  来吧
All right, let's do this.
请坐
Please, sit down.
谢谢你帮忙啊
Thank you so much for helping out.
康妮  你懂的  为你做什么都行
Aw, Connie, you know, anything for you.
谢尔顿
So, Sheldon,
你饿吗
you hungry?
想吃纳西[点心]吗
You want a nosh?
不知道啊  我没吃过纳西
I don't know, I've never eaten a nosh.
不是啦  纳西不是食物
Uh, no, a nosh isn't a thing,
是...  算啦
it's a... never mind.
你要来点硬糖吗
Um, would you care for some hard candy?
这是洁食吗
Are they kosher?
你怎么像我妈一样啊
Who are you, my mother?
好啦  我有何能为你效劳
All right, so what can I do for you?
当犹太人是种什么感觉
What's it like to be Jewish?
烂透了  我不建议
Oh, it's terrible. I don't recommend it.
-为什么  -首先呢
- Why? - Well, for starters,
你会被许多古老没用的条条框框所限制
your life is hemmed in by ancient, pointless rules.
有很多吼来吼去的东西
There's a lot of yelling, and, uh,
然后基本上你也进不了什么好的乡村俱乐部
you're probably not gonna get into a good country club.
那上帝呢
What about God?
祂怎么了
What about him?
祂也是你生活中的一部分吗
Does he play a part in your life?
从历史上来说  祂教训我们教训挺爽的
Well, historically, he's gotten a kick out of punishing us.
那耶稣呢
What about Jesus?
他是犹太人啊
He was Jewish.
我们犹太人出很多名人啊
Oh, we've got a lot of celebrities.
我们有演员威廉·夏特纳
Uh, we've got, uh, we got William Shatner,
还有演员伦纳德·尼莫伊
and Leonard Nimoy...
寇克舰长与史波克吗
Kirk and Spock?
我想当犹太人了
I want to be Jewish.
你先慢着
Hold on a second.
等...  谢尔顿  我有个问题问你
Hold-- I got a question for you, Sheldon.
当你长大之后  你计划留在德州吗
When you grow up, are you planning on living in Texas?
大概吧
Probably.
那我强烈建议你继续信浸信会
Then I strongly advise you to stay Baptist.
能戴个十字架就更好了
Maybe even wear a cross.
那你为什么搬来德州
Why did you move to Texas?
很简单啊
Well, that's simple.
梅德福这里没有犹太人  刚好开放了一个名额
Medford had no Jews, so there was an opening for one.
而你得到了名额吗  太厉害啦
And you got it? Good for you.
我好喜欢这孩子
I love this kid.
我也是
Me, too.
-怎么样了  -很好啊
- How's it going? - Good.
你知道波斯拜火教之祖信仰两个神吗
Did you know that Zoroaster believed in two gods?
我不知道呢
No, I did not.
而道教的人完全不相信有神
And the Taoists don't believe in God at all.
而是相信天人合一  与自然和谐共处
They believe in a principle of harmony.
那他们很棒棒啊
How very nice for them.
谢利  我知道你很喜欢研究东西
Shelly, I understand you enjoy researching things.
爱死了
Love it.
但有一件很重要的事要记住
But it's important to keep in mind
世界上只有一个真神
that there is only one true God.
你这个叫一神论
That's called monotheism.
如果你有兴趣深入了解  我这里有一本书
I have a book about it if you're interested.
没事  我有最重要的"那本书"了
That's okay, I have the book about it.
如果我没选你的宗教  你会生我气吗
Would you be angry with me if I don't pick your religion?
我永远不会生你的气
I could never be angry with you.
你尽情去探索自己真理
You be a seeker of your own truth.
谢谢妈妈
Thanks, Mom.
但如果你探索到的真理是撒旦
And if the truth turns out to be Satan,
那我会与它对战到底
I will do battle with him.
谢尔顿  欢迎你
Welcome, Sheldon.
我们已经等候你多时
We've been waiting for you.
你们是十诫吗
Are you the Ten Commandments?
不是
No.
我们是1
We are one.
与0
And zero.
我们是二进制码
We are the binary code
宇宙的基础
that underlies the universe.
什么十诫只是常见的错误
The ten thing is a common mistake.
我想了解神
I want to understand God.
你们能帮我吗
Can you help me?
你没听懂我们刚才说的吗
Did you not hear what we just said?
这是个二元宇宙
It's a binary universe.
神就是是与否
God is yes and no.
左与右
Left and right.
开与关
On and off.
有与无
Something and nothing.
正与负
Positive and negative.
男与女
Male and female.
光与暗
Light and dark.
那为什么世上会有邪恶与磨难呢
But why is there evil and suffering?
没有邪恶与磨难
Well, without evil and suffering,
又怎么会有正义与幸福呢
there is no good and happiness.
对哦  二元嘛
Oh, sure. Binary.
我们应该告诉他有关
Shall we give him the final piece of information
解开宇宙真相的最终信息吗
that unlocks the secret of the universe?
有何不可
Why not?
世上至少该有一个人了解万物的起源
At least one human being should know the reason for everything.
谢尔顿
Sheldon,
在宇宙出现之前
before the universe began...
傻子
Hey, dummy.
你口水都流到书上啦
You're drooling all over your books.
不要啊
No.
0正准备告诉我那秘密  被你给打断了
Zero was about to tell me the secret and you ruined it.
我之后再也没遇到过1与0
I never heard from One and Zero again.
不过在我得水痘那会儿  9来找过我一次
Although, I was once visited by Nine when I had chickenpox.
他完全没有他自觉的那么有趣
He was a lot less funny than he thought he was.
好的  "神对我的意义"
Okay, "What God means to me."
谁想第一个来
Who'd like to go first?
比利
Billy.
我想当第三个
I'd like to go third.
好的
All righty.
谁要当最勇敢的啊
Who's feeling brave?
米希
Missy.
我当第二个
I'll go second.
好  有人想当第一个吗
Great. Does anybody want to go first?
我来
I'll go.
好的  你上台来  谢尔顿
Okay. Come on up here, Sheldon.
来听听你的想法
Let's hear what you got.
我上周花了一周时间了解别人的信仰
I've spent the last week studying what people believe,
我最后得到了一个结论
and I've come to a conclusion.
是什么
And what's that?
我要创立自己的宗教
I'm starting my own religion.
抱歉  你说什么
I'm sorry, what?
我取名为数学神教
I'm calling it Mathology.
核心主旨是宇宙是二进制的
It's based on a universal binary system.
非常棒  谢尔顿  但这里是浸信会主日学校
That's terrific, Sheldon, but this is a Baptist Sunday school.
我知道  我是来这里改变大家信仰的
I know, I'm here to convert everybody.
-有人吗  -好了
- Any takers? - Okay.
我们去跟你妈妈谈谈
Let's go have a talk with your mom.
数学神教唯一的罪就是当个笨蛋
The only sin in Mathology is being stupid.
欢迎来到数学神教教堂
Welcome to the church of Mathology.
今天我想谈谈质数
Today I'd like to talk about prime numbers
以及它们为何能带给我们喜悦
and why they bring us joy.
赞美上帝
Hallelujah.